FREELANCE JAVA DEVELOPER

David Tortajada

I am a qualified and professional web application developer with more than 10 years of experience in delivering projects for international organizations. Strong commitment to professionalism, excellence, and analytical skills. Team player with an eye for detail.



1

(+34) 655 579 880



mail@davidtor.es



Santander, Cantabria, Spain



davidtor.es

SKILLS

- Web Application Developer
- Problem-Solving
- Fast learning
- Back End Coding
- E-Commerce platform
- · Scrum methodology
- Strong Commitment

EDUCATION

TECHNICAL ENGINEER IN COMPUTER SYSTEMS

Zaragoza University, Spain 2000 - 2006

LANGUAGE

English B1 EOI-Santander. B1 TOEIC. **Spanish** Native

EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE JAVA & INTERSHOP CONSULTANT

Freelance | Cantabria, Spain Nov 2020 - Present

- Java consultant working for Valtech and Wunderman Thompson Commerce clients.
- Develop Web applications with Intershop, Java, and Spring. Oracle and MSSQL databases. Javascript, Node, Git, Jira, Unit test, API, AWS, Azure, Eclipse, Agile methodologies, Linux, Solr, etc.

JAVA & INTERSHOP CONSULTANT

Incentro | Santander, Spain

Jul 2013 - Nov 2020

- Java consultant for clients like Wolters Kluwer NL, G-Star RAW, Coop, Novamedia, Grupo Electro Stocks, Atag, Rechtwijzer, and others.
- Remote work from Spain with Intershop versions 7.5, 7.6, and 7.7 Including a migration to 7.9.
- As a Java consultant, I helped in developing new features, application maintenance, imports, user management, products, catalogs, promotions, content, images, replications, Solr, DevOps, server management, and others
- 24/7 maintenance keeping all servers running smoothly.
- Other skills: ISH Jira Scrum Git Oracle JDK8 Spring Node Scala Angular, Play! framework

David Tortajada

COURSES

- Profesional Scrum Marter Certification, 2020
- Angular 8 Course, 2019
- Cybersecurity course, 2018
- Intershop Developer Course, Jena 2017
- Scala Course, Online, 2014
- Ajax, Asynchronous javascript, and XML. 2010
- EJB3 and J2EE5, 2009
- Spring, 2008
- Java course, 2007

SPORTS AND HOBBIES:

3d printing and design, sport, cinema, travel, mechanics, construction, cooking.

OTHERS

Driving lincense A and B Passion for computers and mobile technology.

EXPERIENCE

C# DEVELOPER

Santander Town Hall | Santander, Spain

Jan 2013 - Jul 2013

- Internal application for the municipal tow service.
- Application and web services in a domain-oriented layered architecture.
- Skills: VS2010, C#, .NET, entity framework, ext.net, WCF, Oracle

JAVA ANALYST

Quality Objects | Madrid, Spain

Aug 2008 - May 2012

- Analyst for the client Mutua Madrileña. www.mutua.es
- Developing web applications with J2EE, RAD (Eclipse), Websphere and DB2.
- Support and maintenance of the Mutua Madrileña
 Website
- Developing and maintaining different internal applications.
- Skills: Spring, Hibernate, Web services, Struts and jQuery Frameworks.

JUNIOR DEVELOPER

Indra | Madrid, Spain

Feb 2007 - Aug 2008

- Development of Insurance Platform for Aviva client:
- Web programming on MVC pattern in J2EE
- UML design on MDA architecture (AndroMDA)
- Java, Javascript, JSP, UML, CSS, Ajax, Struts, Spring, Hibernate, SOA.